翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译   肉松
翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   苏小黛
翻译   草草
翻译   沫沫
时间轴   Kallen
时间轴   念念
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第五季  第十集
"易援"女士
输入安全语句读取文件  区分大小写和空格妈妈把备用钥匙放在哪(四个词  无大写)我最喜欢的棒球运动员(全名)你在奥斯丁的酒店房间留了什么(一个词)
我爷爷说  死人不瞑目
The dead sleep with their eyes open, my grandfather would say.
他们从过去注视着你
They're watching you from the past...
杰姬·夏普
Jackie Sharp.
罗梅洛一刻都没浪费
Romero wasted no time.
你有什么用
What good are you?
你们民主党人真是惊喜不断
You Democrats are full of surprises.
她的律师不让我们靠近她
Her lawyers won't let us get anywhere near her.
因为他们在商量她的证词
Because they're negotiating her testimony.
我们到底是怎么到这一步的
How the hell did we get here?
罗梅洛知道消息  党内有人给他通风报信
Romero was privy to information. Someone from within the party.
他威胁要追究她拉票
He's threatening to go after her for whipping votes
来换取雷米·丹顿先生的竞选经费一事
in exchange for campaign funds from a Mr. Remy Danton,
令人"震惊"的是她和雷米上过床
who, shockingly, she was sleeping with.
她不会因为一段婚外情就作证
Well, she's not testifying because of an affair.
她作证是因为她不想进监狱
She's testifying 'cause she doesn't want to go to jail.
任何人出庭作证都只因为这个
Which is the only reason anyone testifies.
道格  盯住委员会里剩下的民主党人
Doug, keep at the rest of the Democrats on that committee.
确保他们守规矩
Make sure they stay in line.
我会在我党这边发力  但  罗梅洛
I'll keep working my side of the aisle, but... uh, Romero.
他是个混蛋
He's a prick.
一个依然想当党鞭的混蛋
Mmm-hmm, prick who still wants whip.
泰瑞·乌麦克一直忠心耿耿
Terry Womack has been very loyal.
是啊  忠诚和厉害是两码事
Yeah, well, there's loyal, and then there's good.
乌麦克给了你什么
What has Womack brought you?
宣战委员会是他解决的吗
Did he kill the Declaration of War Committee?
11月时他帮你拿下密苏里了吗
Did he deliver Missouri for you in November?
够了
That's enough.
满足他吧
Let's give it to him.
有时你得做出艰难抉择
Look, sometimes you have to make hard choices.
我会跟泰瑞谈的
I'll talk to Terry.
罗梅洛得给他找个地方落脚
Romero's gonna have to find a place for him to land, and...
落在哪我是在意的
where that is matters to me.
就这样吧
That'll be all for now.
好  先生
Yes, sir.
我会让道尔去查
I'm gonna put Doyle on this.
我们已经审查过罗梅洛了
We already vetted Romero.
不  我是说查厄舍
No, I mean on Usher.
尸体保存得非常完好
The body is remarkably well-preserved,
除了手脚  因为都冻伤了
except for the extremities, which frostbite took care of.
但牙齿是完好的
But dental is intact.
我们在南极的同行正在全力配合
Our counterparts in Antarctica are cooperating fully,
12小时内尸体会到我们手上
and the body will be in our possession within the next 12 hours.
报关后我会派人把它运回来
I'll have it in transit after customs.
我们希望尸体在运输中失踪
We'd like the body to get lost in transit.
女士
Ma'am?
它必须失踪
It needs to get lost.
好
Yes.
好  谢谢  助理局长格林
Okay. Thank you, Assistant Director Green.
我们再联系
Uh, keep in touch.
-我还以为你已经睡了  -还不能睡
- I thought you'd gone to bed. - Can't yet.
-那是谁  -我们不认识
- Who's that? - No one we know.
汤姆  我说了  我们不认识
Tom, I said it's no one we know.
你听说过他们在意大利阿尔卑斯山发现的
You ever hear about the 5,000-year-old man they found
冰冻五千年的干尸吗
frozen in the Italian Alps?
没有
No.
他的头骨后面被砸出了坑
His skull was caved in... from the back.
他大概根本没料到
He probably never saw it coming.
被痛打一顿  留下等死
Beaten and left for dead.
留下等死是一个古老的概念
Left for dead is an ancient concept.
当人被冻死的时候
You know, when you freeze to death...
最后会感觉非常热
the last thing you feel is extreme heat.
疼
That hurts.
抱歉
Sorry.
我刚看到了弗兰西斯
I saw Francis out there.
他好像很焦躁
He seems on edge.
能怪他吗
Can you blame him?
好点了吗
Better?
最重的罪是入店行窃
Shoplifting is the worst of it.
近来几次在街上买毒品  而被法庭强制戒毒
A couple of recent street buys that led to court-mandated rehab.
她就在那里生活  工作  买毒品
That's where she lives, where she works, where she scores...
但依我看就是个二十多的女人  努力想活到三十
But all I see here is a woman in her 20s, trying to get to 30.
-她是个威胁  -我不懂
- She's a concern. - I don't get it.
嘉文·奥尔西去委内瑞拉之前  她和他有联系
She was in touch with Gavin Orsay before he left for Venezuela.
-道格  -纳森
- Doug... - Nathan!
你的语气有点急  我们可能得讨论下
There's a bite to your tone that we might need to discuss.
她是个隐患  是个瘾君子
She's a loose end and an addict.
这两样合在一起很糟
That's a bad combination.
重新装修了
It's a clean slate.
唐纳德·布莱斯的品味对我来说太暗了
Donald Blythe's taste was a bit too dark for me,
所以我全拆掉了
so I stripped it all back.
我选了一副画  还在路上
I have chosen one painting so far that's on its way, though.
撒德·彼得森的尸体处理好了
Thad Peterson's body is taken care of.
他叫无名氏
His name is John Doe.
他化成灰我都认识
I'd recognize him anywhere.
这本来会伤害到我国的
This would've been very embarrassing to some interests
一些重要利益
that are important to this country.
我也不希望他的家人看到他这样
And I wouldn't want the family to see him this way.
约旦大使馆有什么消息
What's the news from the Jordanian Embassy?
艾丹·麦卡伦仍不愿
Aidan Macallan still won't
透露他跟佩特洛夫说了什么  没说什么
reveal what he did or didn't tell Petrov.
总统希望他立刻从避难地
Well, the president wants him brought back from his asylum
回到美国
to the United States immediately.
我们应该耐心点儿
I think we should give it a little more time.
我在想让你插手明不明智
You know, I wonder if it was such a good idea to bring you in on this.
-你承诺了  -我知道  艾哈迈迪...
- You promised-- - I know. Ahmadi...
我们派了特种部队去当地追踪
We've got Special Forces on the ground, tracking.
俄罗斯在叙利亚的存在
Russia's presence in Syria
让此事比我曾经想得要复杂
is making this more difficult than I once thought.
我得知道麦卡伦跟佩特罗夫说了什么
I need to know what Macallan told Petrov.
男人制造烂摊子的天赋
It never ceases to astonish me
总能让我吃惊
how talented men are at making a mess.
打击同党对你来说可没好处
Uh, it's not gonna serve you to go after your own party.
你从不放弃
You never stop.
杰姬·夏普不会作证的
Jackie Sharp will never testify.
那她就得进监狱
Well, then she'll go to jail.
艾力克斯  你证明不了他们之间有交换条件
You can't prove it, Alex. You can't prove the quid pro quo.
她好像觉得我可以
She seems to think I can.
如果你换种方式
If you play it a little differently,
还有机会实现目标
you have a chance to get what you want.
我们可以给你党鞭的位子
We're offering you whip.
-我不想要了  -什么
- I don't want it anymore. - What?
天啊
Jesus Christ.
那就财政委员会
Ways and Means, then.
在下次党代会上做主讲
The keynote at the next convention.
我只想让弗兰西斯·安德伍德进监狱
What I want is for Francis Underwood to go to jail.
天呐  这对你有什么好处
My God. How is that gonna help you?
真的  这对你有什么好处
Really? How's it gonna help you?
还有别的办法做到
There's another way to go at it.
你想扬名
Wanna make a name for yourself?
你想让总统生不如死
You wanna make the president's life a living hell?
那就慢慢来
Draw it out.
让委员会继续  但要温水煮青蛙
Keep the committee going but at a slow burn.
你不是为他工作吗
Aren't you working for him?
政府成员  一次找一个人
Members of the administration, you bring 'em in one at a time.
你可以纠缠几年  一边稳住自己的地位
You could ride this for a couple of years and secure your place.
而你压制住总统
While you keep the president in check.
别传唤杰姬·夏普  否则计划会胎死腹中
Don't end it before it's begun by calling Jackie Sharp.
你知道我看好你
You know I see good things for you.
让我为你规划接下来的八年
Let me plan out your next eight years.
与你合作的候选人
The candidates you worked with...
他们中有多少人反复等待
how many of them have waited and waited
误了时机
and lost their moment?
嗯  没错
Yeah, that's right.
我分析当下时局  现在属于我
I'm reading the moment, and this is mine.
让我在第三街下车
Let me out on Third Street.
我送你到雷伯恩大楼
I'll drop you at Rayburn.
不  我总是走最后46米
No, I always walk the final 50 yards.
可能有机会做政治交际
Never know when you might get a chance to press some flesh.
是啊
Yeah.
你好  我是艾力克斯·罗梅洛
Hi, I'm Alex Romero.
我代表亚利桑那州第七区
I represent the Seventh District of Arizona.
我想知道你昨晚失眠的原因
I want to know what keeps you up at night,
我今天好解决这一问题
so I can work all day to address it.
未来属于我们所有人
The future belongs to all of us.
但愿我能得到你的支持
I hope I can count on your support.
你觉得怎么样  马克
What do you think, Mark?
你可是专家
I mean, you're the expert.
就这儿
Right here.
罗梅洛拒绝了  一般的条件他也不感兴趣
Romero said no, and the usual offers don't interest him.
他感兴趣  你只是恨自己感兴趣
Oh, he's interested. He just hates himself for it.
关于委员会的共和党人  我有了进展
I am making headway with the Republicans on the committee.
他们都有不可告人的过去  大多有目击证人
They all have pasts, most of them have witnesses.
无论如何  杰姬·夏普不会作证
One way or another, Jackie Sharp won't be testifying.
那你为什么这么难搞定
So why are you having so much trouble
这位年轻议员
with this one young congressman?
他很固执
He's tenacious.
他让我想起了你
He reminds me of you.
我根本看不出来  我们再联系
Well, I don't see that at all. We'll talk later.
我可以联系丹顿
I could reach out to Danton--
我们曝光他  他就会曝光我们
We expose him, he'll expose us.
那你有什么建议
Well, then what do you suggest?
继续做总统该做的事
That I go on being presidential.
我只有这一个办法
That's the only way that I can deal with this.
我的就职头百天啊
It's my first 100 days, for God's sake.
弗兰西斯
Francis...
我们会捉住艾哈迈迪的
we're going to get our hands on Ahmadi.
世界上再多的艾哈迈迪
There aren't enough Ahmadis in the world.
也抵不掉我们做的那些事
Not for all we've done.
那怎么办
Then what?
比如毁了罗梅洛  这件事总能办到吧
Destroy Romero, for one. Can we at least take care of that?
然后毁谁  整个民主党吗
And then who? The rest of the Democratic Party?
我知道我在做什么  克莱尔  我当过总统
I know what I'm doing, Claire. I've been president before.
我也当过
So have I.
给我接泰瑞·乌麦克
Get me Terry Womack.
你作为副总统的职责是给我建议
Your job as vice president is to advise.
做决定是我的职责
My job is to make the decisions.
泰瑞  没错  我就是问问情况
Terry, yes, I'm just checking in.
我希望你知道我们都支持你
Well, I want you to know that we support you.
那混蛋还想当党鞭  做梦去吧
That bastard asked for whip, but that's never gonna happen.
只要我在台上就别想  我把话给你撂这儿
Not while I'm in this office. I wanted to assure you.
我一向在能出力的地方帮忙
I've always tried to help where I can.
你在卫生和人类服务部帮不上忙吗
And you couldn't help at Health and Human Services?
我们这里做了很多了不起的事
The agency does some amazing work.
你接受采访时曾说那是你梦寐以求的工作
Well, you were quoted as, uh, calling your position a dream job.
人是可以有多个梦想的
It's possible to have more than one dream.
我可以让助手带你逛逛
I can have my assistant give you a tour.
给你看看海地发来的视频
Uh, show you some of the video from Haiti
拍的是过去几个月  我们在那边的
and some of the work that we've been doing there
工作和成绩
over the last several months.
我一定会把
I will be sure to include
你们组织写进我的报道
your organization in the piece I'm writing.
-我相信你们的事业  -谢谢
- I believe in the work you're doing here. - Thank you.
和安德伍德政府合作  感觉怎么样
What was it like, uh, working with the Underwood administration?
他们还行  且这么说吧
They were fine. Let's leave it at that.
我采访过许多非常棒的组织
You know, I've met with, uh, many wonderful organizations so far.
-弗州儿童守卫基金  -他们的工作很棒
- The Virginia Children's Defense Fund. - They do some great work.
塔伯特联盟
The Talbot League?
这个组织也很棒
Another terrific group.
还有安东尼·莫雷蒂纪念基金
The Anthony Moretti Memorial Fund.
他们我倒没什么了解
I don't know anything about them.
他们是器官移植宣传组织
Organ transplantation awareness.
是吗
Oh, is that right?
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
太失礼了  但我又太饿了
It's rude, but I was famished.
谢谢你肯来见我  我给你拿菜单
Thank you for meeting me. Let me get you a menu.
谢谢不用了  我随后还有午餐会
Uh, no, thank you. I have a lunch right after this.
那就好  一定要有个吃午饭的地方
Good. You should always have one on the books.
-戴维斯女士  -你担心艾丹
- Miss Davis? - You're worried about Aidan.
你称呼他有什么昵称吗
Do you call him anything for short?
为什么问我这个
Why would you ask me that?
我不知道总统或者副总统
I don't know if the president, or vice president,
告没告诉你  但麦卡挺好的
has informed you, but Mac is fine.
问题在于他知道什么
It's what he knows is the problem,
他都跟谁说过
and who he may have told it to.
他只想活下去
He wants to stay alive.
没错
Yes.
但这种人才得小心
But those are the ones you have to watch out for.
我上次和艾丹说完话他就上了出租车
Last I spoke to Aidan was minutes before he got in a cab.
我不知道他有什么  也不知道他做了什么
I don't know what he has or what he's done.
我只是奉命行事
I only do what I'm told.
我就在胡佛大楼上班
I'm in the Hoover Building.
那真是全城最丑的一栋楼
It's the ugliest building in... in the city.
我每次进去都闭着眼
I close my eyes as I walk in.
有空来坐坐  尤其是你想找人谈谈的时候
Stop by any time. Especially if you're in the mood to talk.
像你这样口风紧的人  我们用得上
We could use someone who says as little as you do.
丽萨
Lisa!
-我一直在找她  -我不知道她在哪
- I've been looking for her. - I have no idea where she is.
-我帮你拿吧  -不用了
- Let me help you with that. - No. No, I'm okay.
-我很乐意帮你拿  -你吓到我了
- I'm happy to carry it for you. - You're scaring me.
我只是担心她而已
I'm just worried about her. That's all.
我戒了
I'm clean.
很好
Good.
至少我努力在戒  求你别缠着我了
At least I'm trying to get clean. Please leave me alone.
就是
Just...
如果你有瑞秋的消息  请你
If you hear from Rachel, just, uh...
告诉她我全都打点好了
tell her I've taken care of everything.
她可以回来了  不会有事的
She can come home and everything will be fine.
我想她  你知道吗
I miss her, you know?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你不接吗
You going to answer that?
我说得对吗
So, was I right?
你的电话响了
Your phone is ringing.
你按边上的按钮就可以直接挂断
You know, you can just hang it up by pressing the button on the side.
-你不用拒接  -我习惯了
- You don't have to decline-- - I'm a creature of habit.
是的  你是对的
So, yeah, you were right.
这部电话只用过一次  拨打了一个号码
This phone has only been used once to call one number, once.
我用了生产序列号
I mean, I used the manufacturer's serial number
追踪到了它的经销商所在地
and tracked down where it's distributed to.
是在  杜邦环岛的一家商店
It was a, um... A shop in Dupont Circle.
打给了谁
And who did it call?
查无此人
Comes up unknown.
不过前几位数字
But the prefix...
听着  你得找警察或联调局谈
And, look, you're gonna have to talk to the police or the FBI.
-我不能一直  -别担心  我担着
- I just can't keep-- - Don't worry. It's on me.
那个号码的前几位  我看着像政府号码
The prefix on the call, it looks like a government number to me.
喂
Hello.
他跟踪你了  什么时候
He followed you? When?
-我得去  -好的
- I've got to... - Yeah.
好的  如果你觉得现在待的地方安全
Okay. Okay, if you feel safe where you are,
那就待着  我来找你
stay there. I'm coming to you.
有什么不能在电话上告诉我的
So what couldn't you tell me over the phone?
杰姬·夏普
Jackie Sharp.
她怎么了
What about her?
你真不知道吗
You really don't know?
我还以为这事是白宫传出来的
I thought this was coming out of the White House.
马上要爆出来了
The story's about to break
说她拿立法换取竞选资金
that she traded legislation for campaign funds.
消息来源呢
The source?
所以是未经确认的
So, unconfirmed.
一小时内就会上《德拉吉报道》了
It's going to be on Drudge within the hour.
你真没什么要说的吗
You really don't have anything to say?
如果是真的  很遗憾看到民主党
If it's true, it's just sad to see the unexpected fall
一颗曾经的新星这样出人意料地陨落
of a once rising star in the Democratic Party.
得了吧
Stop it.
夏普本能让委员会拿下一分
Sharp would've been a get for the committee.
如果你仍愿意作证  我们就仍愿意谈
If you're still willing to appear, we're still willing to talk.
回见
See ya.
我们这个政府不是这么办事的
This is not how we do things in this administration.
你希望她不作证
You wanted her not to testify.
现在罗梅洛不可能逼她就范了
And there's no way Romero can force her to now.
你让我的新闻发言人
You've put my press secretary
和他的人处于了非常尴尬的境地
and his staff in a very difficult situation.
有人泄密  并不是你
It was a leak, and it didn't come from you.
我真心觉得这样才能占得先机
I really felt this was the way to get ahead of it.
这叫占得先机
This is getting ahead of it?
我向你们保证  她的律师
I guarantee you her lawyers
现在一定让她保持沉默  缄口不谈
tell her to plead the Fifth now, across the board.
最重要的是  对涉及你们的事闭嘴
Most importantly, where it concerns you.
但这都是在我跟佩特罗夫谈判时发生的
But all of this happened while I was negotiating with Petrov.
对大众而言  你当时是第一夫人
Oh, to the public, you were the First Lady,
正不眠不休地守在丈夫的床边
sitting vigil by your husband's bed.
所以这都是在唐纳德·布莱斯的监管下发生的
So, actually, all of this happened under Donald Blythe's watch.
如果你们觉得我越界了  很抱歉
I'm sorry if you think I overstepped.
我是想保护你们
I was trying to protect you.
他做了正确的事
He did the right thing.
我不介意他做了什么
Oh, I don't mind what he did.
我介意的是他做事的方式
I mind the way he did it.
-莉安  -副总统女士
- LeAnn... - Madam Vice President.
抱歉  我的行程太满了
I'm sorry my schedule is so full.
没关系  我非常理解
No, I completely understand,
毕竟你要处理那么多事
with everything that you're dealing with.
抱歉我这么固执
I'm sorry for being so insistent,
但我觉得应该让你知道
but I thought you should
简·戴维斯昨天来找我了
know that Jane Davis came after me yesterday.
找你
Came after you?
她想让我去为她工作  不知你是否知情
She wanted me to work for her. I didn't know if you knew.
为她做哪方面的工作
In what capacity?
这点我还不确定  不过
That, I'm not clear on, but it...
她想要关于艾丹·麦卡伦的信息
She wanted information about Aidan Macallan.
希望你知道我绝不会透漏一个字
I hope you know I would never say a word.
谢谢你让我知道这些
Thank you for bringing this to my attention.
女士  我希望能讨论一下我的前途
Ma'am, I was hoping we could discuss my future.
莉安  我很乐意讨论你的前途  但现在不行
Oh, LeAnn, I would love to discuss your future, but not yet.
如果你愿意  女士  艾丹的事我能帮忙
If you would like, ma'am, I can help with Aidan.
你尽管吩咐
Anything that's required.
很高兴知道你有这个心
That's good to know.
你觉得莉安·哈维不会告诉我吗
Did you think LeAnn Harvey wouldn't tell me?
我从不假设人们会做什么或不会做什么
I never assume what people will do or won't do.
-我以为我们在默契合作  -没错啊
- I thought we were working well together. - We are.
绕过我套取信息
Well, going around me to get information
只会在你我之间造成嫌隙
will only create discord between us.
我并不想这样  克莱尔
I wouldn't want that, Claire.
-戴维斯女士  -总统先生
- Miss Davis. - Mr. President.
抱歉我来晚了
I'm sorry I'm late.
副总统告诉我你的联系人
The vice president has told me that your contacts
再次跟丢了艾哈迈迪
have once again lost track of Ahmadi.
是  我解释过
Yes, as I explained,
叙利亚局势每天都在天翻地覆
Syria is like a different country one day to the next.
这你得归咎于维克多·佩特罗夫
Yes, well, you can thank Viktor Petrov for that.
我是怪他
Oh, I do.
夫人
Ma'am?
我得失陪了  简
Oh, you'll have to excuse me, Jane.
我现在都快忙疯了
The schedule is crazy these days.
当然
Oh, of course.
有没有搞错  国务院加国防部
Really? The State Department, the Pentagon,
连个艾哈迈迪都捉不住
we can't get close to Ahmadi?
我只想要和平
I just want peace.
是啊  和平的利润最丰厚
Yes, there's nothing that makes profits like peace.
而有利润的地方最和平
And nothing makes peace like profits.
总统先生  我能有话直说[迟钝]吗
Mr. President, may I be blunt?
我可不觉得你是迟钝的人  戴维斯女士
Well, I would never accuse you of dullness, Miss Davis.
霍姆斯城将会遭受一场毒气袭击
There's going to be a gas attack happening in the city of Homs.
而如果说  您划下红线
If you were to, let us say, draw a line in the sand...
然后又发生了这样惨烈的袭击
and if this tragic attack were to happen...
那美国政府将不得不
the US government would have
加派三万多名士兵进驻
to send in an additional 30,000 or so soldiers.
以保护石油管线
To protect the oil lines,
阻止佩特罗夫拿下大马士革
to keep Petrov from getting into Damascus.
当然了  还要保护人民
And, of course, to protect the people.
这么大规模的军队几乎就是全面占领了
That's venturing close to occupation with those kind of numbers.
我只是在说  也许宣战委员会
All I'm saying is maybe the Declaration of War Committee
终于可以辩论他们该辩论的了
could finally debate what they were mandated to.
开战
A war.
你认识马克·厄舍吗
Do you know Mark Usher?
认识  我们合作过
Yes, we worked together.
当时他在协助一位众议员
He was handling a congressman.
马克
Mark.
有人给你拿过什么吗
Has anyone offered you anything?
没有  不用  谢谢了
Oh, no, I'm good. Thanks.
你和简·戴维斯合作过吗
Have you ever worked with Jane Davis?
戴维斯是她继父的姓
Davis is the stepfather's name.
一个只干了一任的参议员
A one-term senator.
总之
Uh, anyway, yeah,
她曾对我的一位客户有点兴趣
she was interested in a client I had, at some point.
国会议员候选人
A candidate for Congress.
可怜人  厄舍一意识到他不够强硬
Poor guy. The minute Usher realized he wasn't formidable enough,
就甩手走人  让他自生自灭了
he just dumped him. Let him go.
但马克就这样
But that's Mark.
他擅长发现人才
He has an eye for talent.
喜欢密切关注你  而他自己却站得远远的
Likes to keep you close while he keeps himself remote.
但是他不同意她在一些问题上的立场
But he disagreed with some of her positions,
于是资金就断掉了
the money went away.
听我说  千万别让简骗了你
Listen, don't let Jane fool you.
她看上去可能有点  没有章法
She can seem a bit... haphazard...
但只要他利用完了你
But once he's done with you...
就会像关上开关那么干脆决绝
it's as if a switch gets turned off.
但她冷酷无情
But she is merciless.
要多专一就有多专一
Single-minded as a single mind can be.
怎么了  我今天忘了吃饭了
What? Forgot to eat today.
你给我查出什么了
What have you got for me?
-不知道  -少跟我"不知道"
- I don't know. - Don't do "I don't know."
我去见了梅瑞迪斯·李
Saw Meredith Lee.
我提到了莫雷蒂基金  器官移植
I mentioned the Moretti Fund, organ transplants, uh...
她看起来有点紧张  可是  我说不好
She got a little tense, but... I don't know.
你怎么没告诉我你被开除了
Why didn't you tell me you were fired?
-原来是你  -就是我和你女友说了话
- Oh, that was you? - Who talked to your girlfriend? Yeah.
多久了
How long?
有什么区别  我穷途末路了
What's the difference? I'm tapped.
我们在干什么呢
What are we doing here?
我不喜欢有人在我车上吃东西
I don't like eating in my car.
我觉得劳拉·莫雷蒂的丈夫
I think Laura Moretti's husband
在捐赠名单上被插队了
was jumped on the donor list.
-这你是从哪听说的  -直觉
- Where the hell did you get that? - My gut.
不信我分析给你听
I can lay it out for you.
敢这么说话  你最好说到做到
Yeah, you say something like that, you better.
沙林毒气  主要袭击霍姆斯近郊的平民区
Sarin gas. Mostly against civilians in suburban areas of Homs.
-我们在和一帮畜生斗  -太可怕了
- We're dealing with animals here. - It's horrifying.
你知道我过去一直在尽量克制  但是
Now, you know I've always shown restraint in the past, but...
我打算发布行政命令  部署军事行动了
I'm going to be making an executive order for military action.
先空袭  然后地面部队进驻
Air strikes followed by ground troops.
你得向联合国提交报告
You'll need to present to the UN.
这个情报是哪来的
Where is this intelligence coming from?
简报里都写了
Well, it's all there in the briefing.
但既然我们知道这事会发生
But if we know this is going to happen,
我们为什么不提前制止呢
well, then why aren't we stopping it before it does?
弗兰西斯还留着你的辞职信
Francis held on to your resignation letter.
他想把它撕掉
And he wants to tear it up.
我知道这几个月来你多么艰辛
I know how difficult these past few months have been for you.
我们要求你做了很多
We've really asked a lot.
但等我们部署了军事行动
But once we're on the other side of this military action,
我们会准许你如愿离开政府
you have our blessing to leave the administration if you choose.
但当然  我们更希望你留下
But, of course, we'd prefer if you stay on.
希望这是不言自明的
Hope that goes without saying.
对平民使用
Using weapons of mass destruction
大规模杀伤性武器是战争罪
against civilians is a war crime.
我很感激有机会能完成此事
I appreciate the opportunity to see this through to the end.
我们就希望你会这么说
We were hoping you would say that.
谢谢你  凯茜
Thank you, Cathy.
谢谢  总统先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
你担心她吗
Are you worried about her?
我们得开始想
We need to start thinking about
我们身边的人了
the people we surround ourselves with.
这让我想到了汤姆
Which has made me think of Tom...
他现在已经没理由留在这里了  是吧
who doesn't really have a reason to be here anymore, does he?
没有正式理由
Not an official one, no,
但我想或许我们可以给他个顾问之名
but I thought maybe we could bring him on as a consultant.
当然  这取决于你
Well, of course, that's entirely up to you.
只是一天的时间和精力有限
There's just only so much time and energy in a single day,
我觉得我们该不断自省
and I think we need to constantly be asking ourselves,
"我是否尽可能明智地利用我的时间和精力了"
"Am I spending it as wisely as I can?"
-谢谢  -简  真抱歉
- Thank you. - Jane, I'm so sorry
-从派对上把你叫走  -没事
- to pull you away from your party. - No, no, no.
-当我在电话上听到你的声音  -我就是
- When I heard your voice on the phone... - I just... I just...
-我不知道该怎么办  -出什么事了吗
- I don't know what to do. - Did something happen?
安德伍德夫妇在计划
The Underwoods are planning
对霍姆斯进行空袭  增派军队
air strikes and a troop surge in Homs.
-太可怕了  -你了解这事吗
- How awful. - Do you know anything about this?
佩特罗夫把那里变成了地狱
Petrov is making the whole region a disaster.
没有哪个卷入中东局势的人能得到好处
No one who ever got tangled up in the Middle East came out ahead.
随佩特罗夫去吧
Let Petrov own it.
有可怕的事将要发生
There's something terrible that is going to happen...
我们可以阻止
that we can prevent.
这样啊
I see.
我要向联合国提交我方红线警告
I'm scheduled to present some kind of red line at the UN.
-但我们还可以退一步的  -我要怎么帮忙
- But we can still pull back. - How can I help?
跟总统和副总统谈谈
Talk to the president, the vice president.
我会的
I will.
他们真可怕  是吧
They're terrible, terrible people, aren't they?
简
Jane...
对他们一定要小心
be very careful with them.
当然
Of course.
这是老友的忠告
That's from an old friend.
我们还是朋友吧
Are we still friends?
当然
Of course.
他说总统接受的肝脏
He says the liver the president received
本该是给一个叫安东尼·莫雷蒂的人的
was supposed to go to a man named Anthony Moretti.
他说道格逼迫
And he says that Doug forced
当时的卫生和人类服务部部长
then Secretary of Health and Human Services
把总统排在名单最前
to put the president at the top of the list,
结果莫雷蒂因此死了
which resulted in Moretti's death.
道格还跟他的遗孀发生了关系
Oh, and Doug also has become involved with the man's widow.
干得漂亮
That's a nice touch.
他有证据吗
And does... does he have proof?
关于恋情吗  这个简单
About the relationship? It's easy to prove that.
名单的话  他知道梅瑞迪斯·李有所隐瞒
But the list, he knows that Meredith Lee is hiding something.
他打算再去找她谈
And he's ready to go back and talk to her about it.
你信任他吗
Do you trust him?
我不知道他干吗要编造这些
I don't know why he'd make any of this up.
我在外面
Hey, I'm outside.
你玩得开心吗
Did you have a good time?
我在这种场合已经开心不了了
I never do at those things anymore.
必要之恶
Necessary evils.
不像以前了
It's not like the old days,
你还能结识出人意料的人
when you used to meet surprising people.
是人们不那么出人意料了
Did people get less surprising
还是我们不容易被打动了
or are we less easily surprised?
是啊
Well, exactly.
-我的车来了  -她跟我问了你
- This is me. - She asked me about you.
-我猜到了  你怎么说的  -你...
- I figured. What'd you say? - That you're...
强大  什么的
formidable, etcetera.
我也这么跟他说你的  什么的
Yeah, I told him the same about you, etcetera.
他可以当个伟大的总统
He could be a great president.
但他想做吗
But does he want to be?
而且什么算伟大
And what is great?
还有她
And then there's her.
她怎么样
What about her?
她怎么了
如果鲍勃或泰瑞是副主席
Because if Bob or Terry were the ranking member,
我就找他们了
I'd be talking to them.
我要罗梅洛做光杆司令
I want Romero's clerk stripped.
对  他给委员会成员的任何预算
Yeah, whatever budget he's got for his seat on that committee.
不不  我这是为了党派
No, no, I'm asking for the sake of the party.
杰姬·夏普的事我们躲过一劫  但这事没完
Look, we survived Jackie Sharp, but it's not gonna end there.
事实上  我在因为
The truth is I'm being punished
为我们选民最在乎的事抗争而受惩罚
for fighting for the issues that our base cares most about.
对  谢谢
Yes, and thank you.
道尔说几乎查不到厄舍的任何料
Doyle says there's almost nothing on Usher.
他喜欢赌博  一般能赢
He likes to gamble, usually wins.
但问题是  道尔找过马歇尔
But here's the thing... Doyle spoke with Marshall,
我们知道他离开康威团队时并不愉快
who we know did not have a happy exit from the Conway campaign.
他说  厄舍加入我们政府前
Now, he said that before Usher joined our administration,
他还打算培养罗梅洛竞选总统
he was grooming Romero for a presidential run.
先生  我认为他在两头讨好
Sir, I believe he's playing both sides
这个委员会的目标
of whatever this committee is after.
我不是民主党人  杰弗里
I'm not a Democrat, Jeffrey.
我还是共和党  只是碰巧在白宫工作
I'm still a Republican, just happen to work for the White House.
我是说  趁现在还行  控制下艾力克斯
All I'm saying is let's rein Alex in while we still can.
等他把自己的党派搅翻了天
'Cause after he rips through his own party,
就会去折腾我们党了  不是吗
he'll come after ours, wouldn't you think?
杰弗  你是主席
Yeah, and Jeff, you're the chair...
不  什么  不  听我说
No... What? No, listen.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait! Wait.
你欠我的  我们都知道
And you owe me, and we both know it,
这种事我不会大声说出来
and that's not the kind of thing I like to say out loud.
什么
What is?
什么时候的事
When did that happen?
确认了吗
Confirmed?
嗯
Yeah?
好吧
Yes, well...
沃克要作证
just because Walker's gonna take the stand,
不代表他会说什么  是吧
doesn't mean he'll say anything. Right?
你今早对我说的那个词是什么
What was that word you said to me this morning?
就是现在没人用了的那个
The one no one uses anymore?
黄昏的
Crepuscular.
对了
Right.
一些我最喜欢的动物就是晨昏性的
Some of my favorite animals are crepuscular.
喂
Yes.
什么
What?
什么时候
When?
天呐  该死
Jesus! God damn it!
克莱尔
Claire!
-克莱尔  -我在厨房
- Claire! - I'm in the kitchen.
沃克要作证
Walker's gonna testify.
-什么时候  -最早下周
- When? - Early as next week.
他会说他跟汉默施密特说的那些话
He's gonna say the same thing he said to Hammerschmidt.
不会有新伤害
There's not gonna be any new damage.
-我们不能确定  -我们去找厄舍
- We don't know that for sure. - Let's get Usher.
我早上肯定要找他
You bet I'm gonna talk to him in the morning.
你去哪
Where are you going?
在这房子里找块空荡的地方
To get some goddamn space in this house!
我可以解决沃克  我们给他开条件
I can take care of Walker. We'll make him an offer.
让他回到政坛
A place back on the stage,
去哪个资金雄厚的大学当校长  他会接受的
chancellor of some well-endowed university. He'll take it.
他可能会  但首先
He just might. But first,
我要知道你有罗梅洛什么料
I want to know what you have on Romero.
完全没有
I don't have a thing.
-得了  -道格  别失礼
- Please. - Doug, let's not be rude.
这我难以相信
I find that impossible to believe.
如果我知道  你会知道的
If I did, you would know it.
你和我都是老手了
You and I have been at this a long time.
你愿考虑一个候选人都肯定先审查过他
You wouldn't even consider a candidate without vetting him first.
我觉得艾力克斯很有前途
I thought Alex had a future.
是啊  就我所知可以竞选总统
Yeah, a run for the presidency as I understand it.
他像上浆的白衬衫一样干净
He's clean and crisp as a starched white shirt.
你得做出决定  马克
You're gonna have to make a decision, Mark.
是为我和克莱尔工作  还是怎么
You wanna work for me and Claire, or not?
我已经联络了我自己党派的人
I have already reached out to members of my own party.
我为帮助你动用了我的政治资本
I've used my political capital to help you.
但你还是没回答我的问题
But you're still not answering my question.
我已经回答了
I think I have.
我不需要让你或安德伍德夫人相信我的价值
And I don't need to convince you or Mrs. Underwood of my worth.
认识您很荣幸
It's an honor to meet you.
赛斯  杰弗瑞斯先生稍后会去找你
Seth, Mr. Jeffries will catch up with you momentarily.
我得长话短说了
I'm going to keep this brief.
如果你的说法是真的
If what you're saying is true...
道格·斯坦普救了我丈夫一命
Doug Stamper saved my husband's life.
是的
He did.
还因此害死了别人
And he also cost someone else his.
我猜你是那种有很多欲求的人
Well, I suspect you're the kind of man that wants many things.
但你犯了个错误
But you have made a mistake.
职业上讲  我只有一样一直渴求的东西
There's only one thing, professionally, that I've always wanted.
就是进白宫工作
It's to work in the White House.
赛斯会送你出去
Seth will see you out.
抱歉刚刚不得不走开
Sorry for the interruption.
你说到哪了
You were saying...
凯茜一直是个好人
Cathy was always a very good person.
她内心是的  她有良心
At her core, she has a core.
保佑她
Bless her.
霍姆斯的事对她可能太为难
This whole Homs initiative might be too difficult for her.
你让人很难读懂
You know... you're very hard to read.
这也合理
Which makes sense.
这几年来  你一直左右逢源
For the last several years, you've been a familiar face.
一定很累人
Must get exhausting.
你能跟他一起欢笑的人都很少吧
Must be hardly any people you can even share a laugh with.
你该想想该怎么好好利用我
You should figure out how to take full advantage of me.
我可以帮你如愿
I can help you get what you want.
如果你告诉我你的愿望
If you tell me what it is.
我喜欢帮助他人
I enjoy helping others.
我觉得你知道我的愿望
I think you know what I want.
是啊
Yes...
但你是现在想要  还是四年后要
But do you want it now or in four years?
我要全世界看到艾哈迈迪被逮捕
I want the whole world to see Ahmadi's capture...
铺天盖地的报道
on every news outlet and every screen.
为了党派利益  我更希望沃克先生不要作证
For the good of the party, I'd prefer Mr. Walker not testify.
我在考虑离开宣战委员会
I'm considering taking myself off the Declaration of War Committee.
艾力克斯  你不用那么做
Alex, you don't have to do that.
你可以随意怎么处置它
And you can do what you will with it.
但条件是总统要做正确的事
But that's conditional on the president doing the right thing.
是什么
And what is that?
辞职
Resigning.
再说一遍  我只是为党派考虑
Again, I'm only thinking of the party.
嗯
Yeah...
你他妈以为你是谁啊
Who the fuck do you think you are?
-别对我说粗话  -闭上臭嘴
- Oh, don't use that language with me... - Shut the fuck up.
你根本不知道你在做什么
You have no idea, none, about what you're doing.
请你离开我的办公室
I'd like you to leave my office.
你给我听好
Now you listen carefully to me.
-我说  -闭嘴  艾力克斯
- I said... - Shut up, Alex!
听听这个头条
Here's a headline for you.
"艾力克斯·罗梅洛勾结康威州长
"Alex Romero colluded with Governor Conway
利用宣战委员会
to use the Declaration of War Committee
帮他赢得大选"
to help him win an election."
-没有  -得了  你清楚你做了什么
- No. - Please, you know you did.
-看这多简单  -滚出去
- See how easy that is? - Get out!
听证会上只会有你一个人  我刚见过沃克
You're gonna be all alone at your hearing. I just left Walker.
他打算保持沉默  你会出丑的
He's gonna plead the Fifth. You'll look like a fool.
你想出头  没人介意
You want to be out front? No one has a problem with that.
他们希望你出头  因为你也会倒得最快
They want you there, because you'll be the first to fall.
"为了党派"
"For the good of the party."
做个好梦  议员
Sleep tight, Congressman.
-谁知道威尔的事  -暂时还没人
- Who knows about Will? - No one, not yet.
还有呢
What else?
我现在为什么还要保护你
Why I'm still protecting you at this point...
我自己都不明白
I don't even understand myself.
沃克打算保持沉默
Walker's gonna plead the Fifth.
罗梅洛也不会折腾
And Romero won't rock the boat.
多谢了  马克
Thank you, Mark, I appreciate that.
我建议你安排新闻发布会
I would suggest you schedule a press conference
就在听证会之后
for right after the hearing.
好
All right.
告诉我你做过的最恶劣的事
Tell me the worst thing you've ever done.
不好选
It's hard to pick.
-我说真的  -我也是
- I'm serious. - So am I.
假装爱一个我并不爱的人
Pretended to love someone when I didn't.
可以说  那是最糟的
In a way, that was the worst.
那人知道吗
Did the person know?
她假装不知道
She pretended not to know...
但她知道
but she knew.
她很难受
It was awful for her.
但我为那个错误付出了代价
But I paid for that mistake, too.
那种事  会伤害一个人
Those types of things, they take a toll.
真是奇妙  有些选择毫无意义
It's strange how some choices mean nothing
也有一些会决定你的余生
and others govern the rest of your life.
我做过一些可怕的事
I've done some terrible things.
你不用告诉我
You don't have to tell me.
弗兰西斯杀了佐伊·巴恩斯
Francis killed Zoe Barnes.
克莱尔
Claire.
弗兰西斯杀了彼得
Francis killed Peter.
别说了
Stop.
还会再死许多人
And so many more are gonna die.
别说了
Stop.
我不怕你
You don't scare me.
你该怕
I should.
艾丹
Aidan.
我不叫艾丹了
Not anymore.
你怎么到这儿来的
How did you get here?
有扇门开了  我就出来了
A door opened, I walked out.
听着不太对劲
That doesn't sound right.
我拿到了签证  和今晚的机票  我只是
I got a visa and a flight tonight. I just...
我只是想最后再来看看你
I just wanted to see you one last time.
等等  谁要送你走
Wait. Who's getting you out?
无所谓了
That doesn't matter.
-你说什么了  -其实什么都没说
- What did you say? - Honestly, nothing.
我们必须和安德伍德夫妇谈谈
We have to talk to the Underwoods.
-还是算了吧  -这根本说不通
- Nah, I don't think so. - This does not make sense.
你总是喜欢开好车
Well, you always liked to drive a nice car.
艾丹  跟我来吧  我来解决
Aidan, come with me. I'll fix this.
我还想让你跟我走呢  我也给你备了条出路
You come with me. I've a way for you to get out.
那好吧
Well, all right, then.
等到明天早上再告诉别人你见到了我
Now, don't you tell anybody you saw me until the morning.
我为什么还要告诉别人我见到了你
Why would I tell anyone I saw you at all?
不是吧
Really?
等等
Wait.
-给  拿上这个  -不行
- Here, take this. - No.
拿着  至少上飞机之前要拿着  好吗
Come on. At least until you get on the flight, all right?
我撤了
I'm out.
睡不着
Can't sleep?
外面这么冷  你该披上外套
It's freezing out here. You should have a coat on.
我喜欢
I like it.
别去见沃克
Don't meet with Walker.
我觉得这不是个好主意
I think it's a bad idea.
这会提醒他  他最好该怎么做
It'll remind him of his best course of action.
你错了  我很抱歉  但是你错了
You're wrong. I'm sorry, but you're wrong.
厄舍已经打点好了
Usher has it under control.
你总是想做什么就做什么
You always do what you want.
汤姆不想走
Tom doesn't want to leave.
汤姆没资格选
Tom doesn't get to choose.
外面冷  你进去吧
It's cold. You should go in.
能麻烦你把道格·斯坦普过去三年
If you could get me Doug Stamper's addresses
住过的所有地址给我...
for the last three years...
你知道瑞秋和丽萨的照片条
And do you know what happened to the photo strip
去哪了吗
of Rachel and Lisa?
不见了
It's gone.
我们得自己表明我们的立场
We need to lay out our positions ourselves.
我已经在去纽约的路上了
I'm already on my way to New York.
我不希望你说或者做什么
I don't want you to say or do anything
让你感到不舒服的事
that makes you feel uncomfortable.
我不会和政府立场相左的  我不希望这样
I won't contradict the administration. That's not my wish.
我们需要划下红线
We need to draw a line in the sand.
当然  我还上飞机吗
Yes, of course. Should I get on my flight?
我觉得你最好还是调头回来吧
I think it might be best if you turn around and come back.
听你的
Whatever you think.
就让沃克保持沉默吧
We'll let Walker plead the Fifth.
然后我们再碰头协调立场
Then we'll regroup and make sure we're on the same page.
好吧  调头回去吧
Okay. We need to head back.
"当心纠缠不清的联盟"  总统先生
"Beware entangling alliances," Mr. President.
通常都认为这句话出自华盛顿
You know, that quote is often attributed to Washington,
但其实是杰斐逊说的
but it was actually Jefferson who said it.
总之我想先来见见你
Anyway, I wanted to catch you before,
赶在马克和你的律师来之前
Mark and your lawyer got here.
总统先生
Mr. President.
我知道这对你并不轻松
I know this hasn't been easy for you.
其实一个人的适应能力几乎不可限量
Well, the truth is, one can get used to almost anything.
总之  恭喜你
Well, at any rate, congratulations.
你就要担任国内
You're about to become the chancellor
顶尖大学的校长了
of one of our finest universities.
我们为名誉付出的代价高昂
It's a high price we pay for respectability.
总之  我就是来打个招呼
Anyway, I just wanted to say hello.
并且感谢你所做的一切
And to thank you for all you're doing.
用不了多久
In not too long,
你就会和那些前总统一样
you're going to become one of those ex-presidents
你的成就会让大家
whose work will make everyone...
忘记过去
forget the past.
我也曾是美国总统
I was once the President of the United States.
没错  你的确是
Yes, you were.
然后总统之位被你偷走了  弗兰克
You stole the presidency, Frank.
别这么说  加勒特
Now, Garrett...
都是好久以前的事了
This is ancient history,
但以现代政治的标准来看
but by modern political standards,
我是以压倒性优势当选的
my election was a landslide.
我原本打算改变这个国家
I was gonna change this country.
但后来  发生了一些事
But then... uh, things happen.
人们说谎
People lie...
为与他们同步你只好也撒谎
You lie to keep up.
你一直以来被称赞的优点
The things that you've been lauded for all your life,
突然都成了致命缺陷
those are suddenly fatal flaws.
曾经和你风雨同舟的人
People who've been with you through thick and thin,
你以为永远不会辜负你的人  还是辜负你了
who you thought would never fail you, they fail you.
你会和讨厌的人结成别扭的同盟
You make strange alliances with unsavory people.
当一切清晰起来时  已经太晚
And it all becomes clear way too late.
其他任何人都不会真正明白
And no one else truly understands.
除了就任过的人
Except someone who's been in the office...
你不能指望这个职位
You can't expect the office
能放大你的能力
to do anything more than what you bring to it.
-我这么做是为党的利益  -我知道
- I'm doing this for the party. - I know.
这令人钦佩
And it's admirable.
特莉莎怎么样
How's Tricia?
我们挺好  虽然花了些时间
Well, it's taken time, but we are good.
孩子们也都很好
The kids are doing well.
这只是开始
Well, this is just the beginning.
今后  你我会有更多的合作
You and I are gonna be working a lot more together from now on.
真的吗
Is that so?
道格
Doug.
汤姆  今天上午很忙
Tom, it's a busy morning.
我现在不能提供任何引述
I don't have any quotes right now.
等你有时间  我想坐下来
When you have a moment, i'd like to sit down
问你几个关于丽萨·威廉姆斯的问题
and ask you some questions about Lisa Williams.
不好意思  你在说什么
I'm sorry. What are you talking about?
等你有时间  和我说一声  道格
Let me know when you're free, Doug.
如果你想要一个声明
If you'd like a statement,
赛斯·格雷森的办公室很快会发一篇新闻稿
Seth Grayson's office will be issuing a press release shortly.
你住在杜邦环岛附近  对吧
You live near Dupont Circle, don't you?
我可以正式宣称  是的  我住那附近
I will go on the record and say yes, I do.
沃克总统
President Walker,
希瑟·邓巴的
it's been established in
特别检察官报告中明确称
Heather Dunbar's special prosecutor's report
我们有理由...
that we have reason to--
议员  我已向主席
Congressman, as I mentioned to the chair
和委员会的其他成员提过
and the other distinguished members of the committee,
我建议我的委托人
I am advising my client
目前对关于他就任美国总统期间的所有问题
to plead the Fifth at this time for all questions regarding his tenure
行使第五修正案的权利
as President of the United States of America.
同为民主党人  我得说
I must say, uh, that as a fellow Democrat,
这很不寻常
this is highly irregular.
是的  议员  的确
Yes, Congressman, yes.
但鉴于目前进行的调查...
But in light of ongoing investigations--
其实  我愿意回答议员的问题
Actually, I will answer the congressman's questions.
请提问吧
Please, ask your question.
你任总统期间
Under your administration,
有来自中国商人的数百万美元资金
millions of dollars were illegally laundered
经非法洗钱  影响了美国大选
from Chinese businessmen to affect American elections.
是真的吗
Is this true?
对  是真的
Yes. That's true.
你能否告诉我们
And can you tell us what, if any,
时任副总统弗兰西斯·安德伍德
was then Vice President Francis Underwood's
在其中的参与情况  如果有的话
involvement in this scheme?
他似乎是其中一名总设计师
Well, it appeared to me, he was one of its chief architects.
你这话是什么意思  先生
And, uh, what exactly do you mean by that, sir?
那是他的主意
It was his idea.
马克  你还是去别的地方吧
Mark, I think you need to be elsewhere right now.
我们要对此采取回避态度吗
Are we gonna bury our heads in the sand with this?
不是  你要离开
No, you're going to leave,
副总统和我来决定怎么做
and the vice president and I are going to decide what to do.
沃克食言了  我们说好了的
Walker reneged. We had a deal.
如果需要你  我们会告诉你的
We will let you know if you are needed.
-先生  -这不是请求
- Sir... - That was not a request.
你为什么非要去和他谈
Why did you have to go talk to him?
一定会有出路的  弗兰西斯
There has to be a way out, Francis.
是吗  有吗
Does there? Is there?
这就是我的总统任期吗
Or is this my presidency?
永远是攻击目标
Forever with a target on my back.
被纠缠  被追捕
Haunted and hunted.
莉安  如果你听到这个  说明我死了
LeAnn, if you're hearing this, it means that I'm dead.
1958年以前  美国总统是没有退休金的
所以杜鲁门退休离开华盛顿时  生活极度窘迫
自己开着车回到老家密苏里  买不起房子  只好去亲戚家住
同年的《前总统法案》规定给退休总统发放等额于内阁部长工资的退休金
总统们的退休生活才有了基本保障
克林顿退休时正当壮年  闲不住的他成立了克林顿基金会  到处做慈善
一度成为世界上最影响力的基金会之一
但在2016年大选中  克林顿基金会的募资受到了广泛质疑
一些人指出  许多外国政府和团体可能是因为希拉里做了国务卿才会捐款
大小布什两父子总统  退休后基本上都选择了不问世事的隐居生活
两个人都回到了德州  老布什落户休斯顿  小布什选择了达拉斯
老布什相对更活跃一些  会出席一些公开活动
任上毁多誉少的小布什则更加低调  除了一些必须参加的活动
更多把精力放在了为非洲做慈善  以及支持老兵权益的一些活动中
为打发时间  他还开始学习绘画  而且现在油画作品颇有成就
2016年出版了一本画册  销量非常好
刚退休不到半年的奥巴马  花了很多时间去欧洲和加勒比海度假
随行的都是富商名流  出入都是喷气飞机  豪华游艇
但豪华假日只是表象  奥巴马的手下在华盛顿租了一间办公室
同政府的现任官员联系紧密
现总统特朗普遭遇一连串丑闻后  其支持者指责奥巴马
在背后暗中支持反对特朗普的政治力量
按惯例退休总统都会离开华盛顿
但奥巴马以想保证女儿读完高中为由  退休后在华盛顿租了一间豪宅
不久前  媒体报道他出资八百万美元把这栋豪宅买了下来
看来短期内他是不会离开美国的政治中心了